Xavier University Department of History and Political Science records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Department of History and Political Science records
1937-1977
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Department of History and Political Science
1.5 linear feet (3 boxes)
This is a small collection of documents that reflect some of the activities of the Xavier University History and Political Science Department. Some materials which precede the formation of this department in 1948 are included also.
XUA-72
History of Xavier University Department of History and Political Science
The Department of History and Political Science existed from 1948 until September, 1977. At that time the department was split into the Department of History and the Department of Political Science and Sociology. Prior to 1977, Sociology was the Department of Sociology and Anthropology. In the Fall of 2012 the Department of Political Science and Sociology became two separate departments: the Department of Political Science and the Department of Sociology.
Scope and Content
This small collection gives various documents generated by the Xavier University Department of History and Political Science. Some materials that precede the formation of this department are also included.
Statement of Arrangement
Materials are arranged into series:
Departmental Minutes
Departmental Correspondence and Reports
Course Syllabi and Descriptions
Other Assorted Items
Related Material
Materials stemming from the later reorganization of the Department of History and Political Science into two separate departments may be found in departmental collections for those disciplines.
Restrictions on Access
Some materials may have restricted access. Please contact the archives staff.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
History--Study and teaching; Political science--Study and teaching
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Departmental Meeting Minutes, 1946-1977
  - Departmental Minutes, 1946-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Departmental Minutes, 1961-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Departmental Minutes, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Departmental Minutes, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Departmental Correspondence and Reports, 1938-1976
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1938-1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1957-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Course Syllabi and Course Descriptions, 1957; 1966-1976; undated
  - Course Syllabi, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Course Descriptions, 1966-1976; undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Other Assorted Topics, 1937-1973
  - Course Textbook Information, 1947-1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Members of the Departmental Faculty, 1967-1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Comprehensive Examinations in History, 1937-1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Thesis Project Appraisals, 1950-1967 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - National Defense Education Act Program, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Speeches, 1950-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    This folder contains various speeches, mainly by W. E. Shiels, S.J..
  - Phi Alpha Theta/ Kappa Nu Chapter (Honor Society), 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)